<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0">
	<properties>
		<title>log4j-aws-appenders changes</title>
	</properties>

    <body>
        <release version="1.2.0" date="TBD" description="support for SNS as a destination">
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                Add SNSAppender, intended for notification of runtime errors.
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                Allow discard threshold and action to be reconfigured at runtime.
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                If there's an initialization error the internal message queue is set to discard
                all messages (avoids memory issues, especially with an unbounded queue).
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                CloudWatchAppender and KinesisAppender now fail to initialize if given an invalid
                destination name (would try to make them valid).
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="1.1.3" date="2017-12-12" description="improved testing, minor bugfixes">
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                Bugfix: CloudWatchAppender now handles multi-part results from DescribeLogGroups and DescribeLogStreams
                (should be unlikely given that we're using exact matches, but possible in sites with large numbers of
                similarly-named groups or streams).
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                Bugfix: KinesisAppender is now more resilient to rate limiting during initialization. This was an issue
                with integration tests, which create and delete streams at a high rate. It is not likely to occur in
                "normal" operation, unless a large number of applications start logging at the same time (which could
                happen if a fleet of instances started up).
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                AbstractLogWriter now tracks whether an error happened during initialization. This is currently used
                for testing, but will be exposed via JMX at some future point.
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="1.1.2" date="2017-10-16" description="JSON output">
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                Added JsonLayout, intended for use with Kinesis/Firehose/ElasticSearch deployments
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="1.1.1" date="2017-10-10" description="Message discard">
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                Added configurable message discard, to avoid out-of-memory errors when
                connectivity to AWS is spotty
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="1.1.0" date="2017-09-29" description="KinesisAppender">
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='add'>
                Initial implementation of KinesisAppender, which writes to a Kinesis stream.
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                Improve implementation of CloudWatchAppender, including integration tests
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="1.0.1" date="2017-09-02" description="Bugfixes">
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                CloudWatch SDK dependency not marked as provided; might cause conflict
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                Default configuration incorrect: log stream name was "{startTimestamp}", should be "{startupTimestamp}"
            </action>
            <action dev='kdgregory' type='update'>
                Initial group/stream creation could fail if multiple writers initialized in short order
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="1.0.0" date="2017-08-12" description="Initial public release"/>
	</body>
</document>
